<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flexbox on Eric Carlisle : UI Developer, UX Designer</title>
    <link>https://www.ericcarlisle.com/tags/flexbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flexbox on Eric Carlisle : UI Developer, UX Designer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>eric@ericcarlisle.com (Eric Carlisle)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eric@ericcarlisle.com (Eric Carlisle)</webMaster>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.ericcarlisle.com/tags/flexbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridiculously Easy Layouts with Flexbox</title>
      <link>https://www.ericcarlisle.com/presentations/2016/03/10/ridiculously-easy-layouts-flexbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eric@ericcarlisle.com (Eric Carlisle)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ericcarlisle.com/presentations/2016/03/10/ridiculously-easy-layouts-flexbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    Ready to have your mind blown? Meet Flexbox! The Flexbox (or Flexible Box) Layout Model is a set of CSS attributes that will likely change the way you think about UI layouts. Flexbox uses a dual-axis, container/item layout model allowing for powerful approaches to element space distribution, alignment, and sizing. This can be a tremendous boon for web projects with dynamic data and design flux. It may also tremendously simplify responsive layouts that are dependent on commonly complicated grid models.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    This presentation will introduce the mechanics of the Flexible Box Model and demonstrate its capability for simplifying markup and styling. Comparisons will be made to other layout paradigms to illustrate strengths of the model.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New UI : Staying Strong with Flexbox, SASS, and Mustache.JS</title>
      <link>https://www.ericcarlisle.com/presentations/2014/09/13/staying-strong-flexbox-sass-mustachejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eric@ericcarlisle.com (Eric Carlisle)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ericcarlisle.com/presentations/2014/09/13/staying-strong-flexbox-sass-mustachejs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    The last few years have seen spectacular, sweeping changes in the paradigms of front-end website production. New technology standards, frameworks innovations, design trends, and the always-growing mobile market have totally reshaped approaches to building the presentation layer.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
    This hands-on lab will investigate a powerful medley of front-end production frameworks, standards, and tools.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
